[Music]
join us as Auto X durs 17 we are almost
adults emphasis on the word
almost
but what we've learned through our
adolesence is how to test cars and bikes
to near destruction to tell you which
ones are the absolute best of the
Year this is the Auto X best of 2023
Mega test emphasis on the word Mega why
you act like
why why want to move that
you why you want act like that why you
play
[Music]
hard all right so it's been a hectic
couple of days we have had a lot of fun
a lot of vehicles to test so we thought
that we'll come back recollect our
thoughts maybe calm down a bit and then
talk about our experience was and of
course starting of this conversation is
our editor-in chief duu Bell duu how
were your last couple of days I'm just
getting my heart rate to settle down a
little bit uh it was good fun it's
always good fun um we say that you know
why do we do this big Mega test every
year and mainly we do it because it's
fun but we we also do it because there's
a little bit of method behind the
madness so that's what we're going to
get into right so uh i' if you guys have
seen our earlier videos I actually said
this is my first year here what a
surprise seeing the lineup just shows
the extent that we are willing to push
to find out what is the best of 2023 but
here's the thing our tag is best of 2023
right so for you what does what makes
the best of
2023 I mean the great thing about doing
every year year after year after year is
that when you collect everything
collectively in one place then it gives
you two things one it tells you what are
the standout vehicles of the year and
the other thing it tells you what the
trends are over the years so it's really
nice to compare something one after the
other and compare something at different
ends of the spectrum so you've got the
ultra fast Ultra Luxury uh Ultra
economical and uh very usable so I mean
it's really nice to be able to do all of
that in one place at one time it gives
you a really great perspective for the
whole sort of everything that's
available so year after year of testing
and this is the 17th year so the mega
test is almost adult now so how much did
we push this year so this year frankly
we pushed it quite a bit because
normally our home for this test so far
has been the Bic and the bic is amazing
right it's a phenomenal facility it
doesn't get any better but it also has a
lot of margin for error so you can do
like stupid stuff and not have to worry
um this year we were doing it at the IAD
testing center in maner for the first
time um and it's an amazing facility but
it also has the guard rails which are
right around the test track with no
margin for error so you can push it but
you also have to be a little aware of of
what you're doing um but the great thing
is that look we're not trying to push
something to 1010 for no reason we're
just trying to uh push something Beyond
its normal everyday limit so you expose
any flaws that might exist and you want
to push every vehicle uniformly to the
same sort of limit uh just so you get a
sense of what each one can do at its
very extreme when you just get it a
little bit outside the comfort zone then
you really get a sense of what's
underneath right so speaking of the IAD
facility uh lot of cars to test how was
the facility in itself how was the
experience to test because there were
different obstacles that we had set up
and you of course set the fastest lap
times in all the cars that were there so
how was it for you so the facility again
was fantastic right initially we were a
little apprehensive because we thought
it's just going to be two uh Corners
with the banking at either end and
connected by two Straits um but we mixed
things up as you said we put uh we used
a bunch of a few dozen cones to very
good effect so the banking was great
because it's sort of positive cber it's
concrete it's a little rough it's a
little bit of undulation because of the
nature of the banking you can carry a
lot of speed through the corners but
it's not only the grip level it's also a
real test of the suspension because of
the undulation and the banking and the
concrete surface so it really puts a lot
of pressure on these vehicles so it
gives you grip levels it gives you
vehicle Dynamics it gives you like
absolute extent of what the suspension
is capable of coming off the banking we
put in uh chicane so you come off the
banking you've got a little left right
left kind of Kink chicane uh then we
added a slum as you go further down the
straet so again it gives you another
nice sort of variable and um changing
grip levels and variability of the way a
car handles Etc then you've got the
banking at the other end and we put an
emergency braking Zone accident
avoidance kind of section at the other
end so again like really test the
braking really test not only the
Dynamics of the vehicle but also the
electronics um and then you've got the
straight at the uh at the other end and
then you're going into the banking again
at high speed so it had a little bit of
everything so it was it was really good
it worked out very well before I get to
the individual cars because we have an
exciting lineup as you guys know I want
to first know what was your thought when
you saw the lineup because we had about
30 cars over there the first glance sure
it's breathtaking but because it's the
17th time that we've put the best
contenders not just all the cars but the
best cars which are fighting for the
highest spot so what was your take on it
where do you see the 2023 lineup so like
we've seen over the last few years uh
it's the EVS which are starting to
slowly sort of take center stage they're
starting to be there in much greater
numbers and it's across the entire
Spectrum now so you've got the Thiago
and the EC3 at one end which are very
affordable um you've got ionic which is
sort of somewhere in the middle which is
premium yet practical yet usable it
doesn't completely uh destroy your bank
account uh then as you get higher up the
Spectrum I mean you've got everything
that goes all the way up to the i7 which
is in another Stratosphere it's like a
paradigm shift so uh and and so many in
between right you've got the Volvos
you've got the mercs uh you've got a I
mean if if you want to go green uh and
you have a budget you can go at any end
of the spectrum uh and you've got really
great usable cars that you can choose
from right so uh now that we've come to
the cars what were the cars that stood
out for you and why so I mean I
mentioned the i7 being a paradigm shift
uh it's a complete paradigm shift I mean
that thing is like it's Space Age
firstly that Grill hits you in the face
and I've been very critical of the BMW
Grill so far but somehow in the i7 after
that initial sort of shock and awe uh it
works the only thing that I still find a
little objectionable is that LED strip
around the grill uh at night but uh
other than that I mean that thing is
amazing I mean whether you're sitting at
the back and it's got that huge 31 in uh
screen the lights the materials the just
the screens everywhere uh and then when
you drive it I mean it is insane um so
one of the big things uh over the years
again has been how these vehicle
manufacturers have been able to almost
be physics defying in their engineering
um I mean we had the Cayenne we had the
i7 we had a bunch of these vehicles I
remember driving a Cayenne GTS in lunala
like 10 years ago um and at that time it
was phenomenally fast but on these tight
twisty roads you would get on the brakes
and you would then get a sense that okay
wait this is a big heavy SUV but that
perspective has totally shifted now you
drive an i7 or an eqb or some of these
EVs and they're stupendously fast but
there's nothing that you get so away
from the fact that they big and heavy
you get into a Cayenne after that and
you're like wow this feels really light
and agile and that's how your sort of
perspective has has shifted and yet um
what these manufacturers have been able
to do to get these vehicles to feel fast
and agile I mean with the i7 it was
mind-blowing between I don't know
whether it's just the four-wheel
steering or how they've been able to do
it but especially like through the slum
you feel like you're piloting a little
hot hatch and you get out of the car and
you think what the hell this thing is
huge um and then of course at the other
end of the spectrum you've got an Urus
which even in the past we've had a
performance car of the year being an SUV
the Aston Martin dbx was the performance
car of the year a few years prior so
performance car and performance bike is
simple whichever car or bike is the
fastest around the track at any given
year gets the performance car bike tag
this time it was it was Theus by a long
shot um so technically it's performance
SUV U but that's how the Paradigm has
shifted as as the market has gone to
SUVs as the market has gone to EVS big
heavy cars don't feel so big and heavy
anymore so that's the big Trend um but I
mean there are the other trend is that
you don't have any Vehicles now that you
can point to or point at and say that
this is not a well engineered good
machine I mean across the board now
which makes our job so much harder cuz
you have to choose between these these
vehicles which are all great I remember
because we th the top boss right so we
have to sit together and sort of we
can't get away with bias per se because
that's how foolproof our scoring system
is because it averages things out but
when it come when it came to the i7 oh
it was it was difficult to mark it down
yeah right yeah where do you mark it
down other than on price because it's
stratospheric even in its price but what
a machine and and the uh the fact that
you're saying it was fast I remember it
because I was uh coordinating the cars
coming in and out and I remember the i7
breaking just so early but at the same
time going by so fast it it was a side
yeah third fastest car of the lot and
bloody i7 huge massive luxury sedan
amazing but was it the biggest surprise
this year uh yeah I think so I mean I
it's a BMW it's a 7 Series you expect it
to be as uh engaging even to drive as it
would be to sort of sit in and luxuriate
in as it were but uh the fact that
they've taken an EV and they've been
able to engineer it like this just shows
what these car companies now are capable
of doing with these EVS I mean you
expect an e to be stupendously fast I
mean the second fastest car in the test
was the Volvo C40 recharge and
ridiculously fast like just crazy fast
um the only difference is that um the
the way these EVS deliver power it's
still like an onoff switch um versus now
a really well engineered internal
combustion engine vehicle because we're
really at the epitom me of what is
possible with internal combustion right
I mean it's it's sort of reaching the
peak and then I don't want to say
downhill but let's say it's a transition
period so I'm really enjoying uh the 100
Years of engineering or whatever you
want to call it that's gone into making
the ice vehicles that we have today
because they they're amazing I mean
everything from a Cayenne to a C3
aircross was just really nice to drive
it's it's uh it feels organic it feels
more connected
uh it feels more linear I mean I I love
them right but um what we also do what's
beautiful per se about what we test is
at the same track the same testing
facility as you mentioned we have the
tagos and the EC3 so we have the other
side of the spectrum both in electric as
well as the mass Market cars so in there
was there something that really stood
out apart from uh all the cars you drove
was surprisingly uh even the comet was
was fun to drive I mean it's little and
it's you but it it went over 100 kilm an
hour I remember the guard
saying um and it did it was comfortable
really comfortable and stable at 105 or
whatever top speed it touched on the on
the straight and even going through like
the the slum and stuff at no point did
it feel like we were asking too much of
it so um uh everything across the board
has just sort of move slowly moving the
game forward um and everything from the
the Elevate to even like a Fran or an
EXA I mean at any end of the spectrum
you have these vehicles that are really
properly engineered and fun to drive um
and and that's that's something that we
have a a soft spot for um and as part of
our marking we also have X Factor which
is that little extra something that
vehicle brings to the table it's one of
the few subjective factors that we have
in our in our scoring uh and there's a
lot of X Factor across the board uh to
be found uh and like you said all our
scores get averaged so we we publish all
the scores across the parameters across
the vehicles um Everybody votes uh and
then scores get published so we try and
be as sort of scientific and objective
about this as as possible yeah and like
that was a surprising bit for me
honestly I mean I know this is about the
track experience and but for me
personally a mega test or an award test
which publishes scores transparently I
mean that I've not seen that happen at a
lot of places if any if I may say so but
uh We've Spoken a lot now I sort of want
to put you on the spot and ask some
rapid rapid fire questions so if you
were to steal a car which one would that
be um I would steal an i7 cuz I would
never would pay for it in any Universe
um but it doesn't have to be an i7 right
like we were talking about X Factor
something like a jimney uh I mean it's
something that I've really been looking
forward to uh I've owned and rallied a
gypsy so I was really looking forward to
it uh the problem with having high
expectations is that many of times it's
not met um with the jimney I think that
uh that it certainly was uh was met and
uh so you can have a lot of fun and have
a vehicle with a great X Factor um even
at at a lower price point so it's got an
amazing character the the other thing
that I want to highlight during our test
is we also did a bit of a tire test cuz
we had one jimney on stock tires and one
jimney on slightly wider rubber um and
the difference between the two in terms
of how they handled at the limit was
like amazing uh there was a stark
difference in the way the front end
responded and how it handled and grip
levels and stuff so uh I would buy a
jimney but I would change the tires on
day one yeah lot of potential there for
sure your most surprising car
test um the Volvo C40 it was just
ridiculously fast I mean just insane it
was faster than a Cayenne um and again
it just points to what these
manufacturers can do with uh these
electric vehicles now yeah and I mean
the elevator as well because it's a
Honda and it's got that sort of very
smooth all the way at um at the rev
limit um so I mean there were there were
a lot of actually one more the in Inova
and the invictor both of them just
supremely comfortable like usable now
hybrid so more economical really really
comfortable U so I mean there was
something for me car that maybe left you
wanting a bit more where you see the
potential and it just has to unlock
it um I mean we're talking about EVS so
like the Thiago is a great starting
point um for EVS and at a price point
which is Affordable and and it's usable
and stuff but I think it still needs
that little bit more to be truly usable
so maybe like a Nexon uh extended range
is is more usable but a little more
expensive U but at that end of the
spectrum I think yeah there's like even
the the EC3 it left uh a little bit to
be desired in terms of uh what you
you're getting at the absolute base end
of the EV spectrum and the the most
confusing car
it could be in a good way maybe a
hux um because again it's like it's so
big it's so big that you really you
really want to like it right because
it's it's got this really Butch appeal
um but on our roads it's just it's not
that that usable I mean it's
indestructible completely indestructible
and it's got that X Factor U so I really
wanted to like it but it just felt dated
from behind the wheel it felt big and
lumbering and um so I really I I had
expectations going in um and then I
drove it and I was like I don't think I
could do this on a regular basis yeah
but like it still scored very well on
the xfactor it's one of the highest
scoring xfactor cars so yeah I mean it
makes it's really got something going
for itself one last
question when it comes to the best of
2023 we know what makes the owner so
coveted but what does a car need to be
to become a best of 2023 I mean it
needss to be outstanding right it needs
to be outstanding it needs to be great
at everything that it does and then it
needs to have that little extra special
something that's why we have X Factor as
part of the scoring and a big part of
the scoring because all of us love
Vehicles right we love what we do uh we
love testing these vehicles and but it's
that little something that needs to
appeal to you to really stand out and
make it a best of vehicle right right
thank you very much much it's been a
pleasure now I'll catch you guys for the
next
[Music]
jwy all right so now we're sitting down
with our managing editor ishan isan
first question first yes how has the
past couple of days been for you uh past
couple of days have been um exciting
very very busy slightly exhausting but I
mean this is something that we do every
year so I'm kind of sort of used to it
by now so yeah you get all the cars
together you get all the bikes together
you set up uh the the circuit that
you're using you set up your equipment
you set up um um the whole flow of
events so yeah it's it's it's a bit
chaotic but that's okay I mean when
you're trying to do so many things in
such short time uh that's how it's going
to eventually play out right so we had a
long lineup of cars this year 28 of them
competing for the top SP
spot what I want to ask is when you saw
the full lineup of cars which one was
the first that spoke to you the one you
wanted to grab the case for uh that's I
I I don't think I have one I mean that's
always the case every year that um I I
hadn't driven the new uh version of the
Cayenne so of course that that was one I
hadn't driven the i7 so that was the
other in the smaller cars I wanted to
throw the jimney around for for obvious
reasons um I've driven the elevator bit
so that was also there I wanted to test
the new petrol engine on the um the SOS
because that 1.5 is very powerful uh of
course the luxury cars the lexuses the
Audi's the BMWs all of those are there
uh it's a nice uh mixed bag I also
wanted to test the smaller EVS because
we had a much larger number of them this
year so yeah lots of them but one of the
standouts I would think and it's a very
left field Choice um I really wanted to
see what the new Lexus L could do it's
huge it's never meant to be on track uh
but it's something I really admire and
that was one of the cars I really wanted
to drive but was it your lasting memory
oh yeah it it is a lasting memory it's
it's a very different kind of a machine
um uh essentially U it's massive so if
you're driving it on the road you really
feel the size you have to be really
careful in urban traffic especially the
two wheelers around us um but yeah it's
it's a machine you can take anywhere
it's got Lexus levels of Lu JY uh so
yeah it's sort of it's it appeals to me
in the same way that one of my favorite
cars is the Mercedes G Wagon this is
let's say a similar idea slightly larger
slightly different but yeah you you're
basically looking at the same thing with
both cars so yeah it does speak to me to
an extent I'm an old school guy so yeah
that that works for me yeah so if I were
to ask you baring thex if you were to
pick up one of the keys of the entire
lot and not the performance the cay what
which keys are you going for that's
that's that's interesting which Keys am
I going for I'm going for the Cs I'm
definitely looking at that because
that's always been a proven product new
engine uh then in the newer cars I would
tried to sort of Drive the Elevate again
the C3 aircross of course which was a
car I drove when the first media drive
happened uh very surprising I didn't
have expectations and it really really
did well uh on a lot of factors the C3
air cross scks up a lot of boxes um
other than that maybe one of the EVS um
the GLC also I would say okay you know
they've done a evolutionary upgrade to
the second gen GLC but it drives very
well it's really good inside so it's
it's a it's a surprise
card um see you've been doing these Mega
tests for a while now you've you've
driven every car under the sun that's on
sale on India but
when you put the contenders for the best
of 2023 together you already have a good
lot yes so what was the car that was the
most difficult to critique for
you I mean let's leave out the Urus and
the cayen again um the i7 was very
difficult actually it wasn't very
difficult to critique because I look at
it and I'm like yeah what is this but
yeah you step inside the car it's
amazing you drive the car it's
absolutely phenomenal so um n was
slightly difficult to critique um I
think let me flip this question
slightly before it was launched I would
have thought that the Jiminy would
be the next big thing but you get inside
the car you start driving it it's
actually very easy to critique there are
quite quite a few points that you can
pick off but it also has as advantages
um other than that what was difficult to
critique I mean the Q3 was very
difficult to critique um it does very
well on most fronts so very hard to
critique that actually even harder to
critique than the X1 because X1 has a
couple of flaws especially for a BMW the
C40 was very difficult to critique yeah
so both of those cars were they were
really really up there I mean you really
had to be looking for faults to pick out
something or nitpicking to sort of you
know uh critique them actually if you
ask me the question which is easy to
critique that's very easy to answer
difficult to critique is a difficult
question final question
isan when we talk about the best of 2023
right we have a lot of parameters most
of which we publish but for you because
at the end of the day it's multiple
jurors coming together averaging our
removing buyers and picking a winner but
for you what makes a car like what what
should a car have to be the best of
2023 see this is very subjective now I
I'll I'll make it clear this is not I'm
not saying this is auto X's philosophy
I'm saying this is My Philosophy uh
subjectively speaking I come from the
old school uh uh Enthusiast uh culture
for me the fundamental uh the first
thing I look for is how a car drives how
the engine is how the steering is how
the gearbox is how the suspension set up
how it handles that for me is top
priority uh of course I will look at
practicality I want a car to be spacious
like I said about the jimy the one thing
I really hate about it is that you don't
have enough cubby holes around you so if
I want to store my wallet and my phones
and keep a couple of things a bottle of
water it's virtually impossible which is
really really annoying in today's world
because I mean these are prerequisites
for any I mean if this is 1990 and we
driving an 800 and we didn't get all
this I would understand but in 2023 so I
mean these kind of things those matters
space matters practicality matters um
and I think then ultimately for an
Indian customer even for me okay I'm
will let's say if it's a really
enthusiastic car to drive and it doesn't
give me that good fuel efficiency I'm
willing to work with that I have no
issues I can deal with it but the
overall value for money aspect that am I
paying the right kind of
money uh for a product for the
experience for the experience for the
overall product for the Driving
Experience how the comfort is how the
practicality is is it worth the money
all right now that we understand I know
I said last question but I just want to
throw in one more
was there a car that fit that
description multiple cars did um we can
look at the question in two ways let's
say budget no problem that's one way of
looking at and I think the C40 comes
very close yes it has a couple of flaws
the Bri seat is too small and all that
but it's got a fantastic powertrain it
runs brilliantly quite nicely equipped
and it's a decent price the Q3 also does
it actually you know okay I would like a
little more power than just me I there's
enough power it's fast enough uh and it
does the job it has it has the
practicality it has it's quite desirable
um I mean of course the cayen we can
talk about the Urus all that is an
obvious um um you know answer the LX
yeah if I if I'm only doing long distan
yeah I would rather take that you can
literally take it anywhere um in the
affordable segment now that's that's a
very good question I I don't know if
there's a car that ticks all the boxes
today wow it's it's actually that's been
the case for a few years now um in the
affordable segment to get a car that's
genuinely nice to drive quick um and
value for money and also as the
practicality I
think with running costs being what they
are um uh manufacturers now focus on
efficiency they focus more on creating
products that appeal to a wider audience
because let let's be honest me as a
driver I'm looking at it from very very
narrow prism of what I want so this year
affordable
segment no I I had huge hopes for the
jimin but no it it it still needs at
least 30 more horsepower to be to
qualify in my in my book as an absolute
must buy and there are a couple other
factors lots of promising cars lots of
great cars for uh if you are just a
regular commuter in want a practical car
some something like a Elevate or
something like in high cross but are
they as engaging to drive no they they
still lack that final 5 10% so we can
say there is one this is the jimney but
it needs some work it needs work no all
of them see if if we look at it that way
then a lot of the cars can be there but
they all need that final 10% of magic to
make them that desirable all right thank
you isan it's been a pleasure great
insights thank you very
much
[Music]
keep the funing air
[Applause]
music okay so next up I have Mr shiang P
our in-house road test editor shiank
you've been on the car Journey you've
driven a lot of cars in the past couple
of days how has it been for
you I think it was overwhelming lot of
hard work yeah sometimes you forget lots
of cars and you have to take care of
different things you have to have fun
also you have to do the shoot also you
have to evaluate each and everything you
have to also see that you're not getting
carried away by certain cars in the
sense because some who are like black
and fast black and fast yeah so you're
like okay with the V12 and you're not
kind of biased to one car because you
are in this setting where you know it it
kind of gives advantage to a certain
kind of car or cars so yes it's
difficult but of course we put it
together and it was fun there was a good
lineup of cars there first before I get
to how you found the cars I want to
understand from your perspective what
makes a car a best of
2023 I think for me and I'll quickly
leap to conclusion here I think for me a
car
it has to make you feel special and it
also has to kind of meet all the other
criterias I I just quickly give you an
example the car that was my favorite
from this bunch is the maruti Suzuki
jimy because for me that was the best
launch of the year because to me it's
not the perfect car it's flawed but it's
a car that speaks to me it's a car that
it kind of brings you know that love for
cars that kid in me alive it looks like
gas it can do off-road
it's not onedimensional it can also be
your only car so for me a car has to
make you feel special but at the same
time it has to do car things as well so
for me a car best of 2023 of course we
have different cars and uh great lineup
again but for me a car has to make you
feel special while also being not
perfect but it has to do so we can say
the secrets out Yeah you sort of have
given away one of your top contenders
yeah exactly but there are many cars
because we had what 27 cars there were
many cars that were great fun also a lot
of character special so so other than
the jimney what stood out for you I
think the hyai anic 5 same thing it
looks other worldly in the sense how
it's designed kickass when you drive it
there is no Hyundai element even though
Hyundai cars are great now but it's rear
whee driven it's got a powerful motor
it's spacious it's Tex C and it's a game
changer in that sense so I think that is
a car again that feels very special the
moment you park that car you sit in that
car you drive it everything about that
car is special so for me the ionic 5 is
another car that was very special in
every area and at the same time it also
excels being a car being a commodity
that it is transporting yeah practical
spacious great range so for me that's
what makes a car sort of best of 2023 so
if you had to steel one of the keys to
the car is the ionic what you no it's
the Lamborghini of course Theus per
because it is the car that it's the
bucket list I'd say to in fact that was
the first Lamborghini that I ever drove
but the question then comes is is the
performante
your memory that
stays is this is this the most memorable
time that you had during the last no of
course because it is a memorable car but
not the right setting because I was
there as a tester so I was testing oh
what's this car doing you know I was not
kind of I was enjoying it but uh I think
in the larger scheme of things the
Lamborghini is not probably the top I
think the again to come back to uh the
ionic 5 I think that was a car that kind
of surprised me the most and again I'm
forgetting I I am forgetting here the
BMW ice
seven that is a car that both electric
actually you'd be surprised because by
now our viewers have seen multiple jury
members sit here and tell me the i7 is a
reccurring theme yeah why do you why do
you think that is I think the i7 it's
basically when I saw that car on the
internet before it was launched before
we got to drive it I hated it because I
thought it looked very controversial all
BMW designs are like that but the i7 I
thought it was to put it mildly it
looked ugly right but uh I didn't like
it at all but then I got to drive it and
you know the moment you sit inside that
car the whole perception just
changes it kind of takes the game
forward it is a paradigm shift in terms
of what you get inside that car and then
the luxury inside those screens you know
everything it feels like a theater and
it completely changes the game and the
best part then you get to drive it right
that's where it feels so BMW it doesn't
feel synthetic it doesn't feel like you
know BMW has lost its charm it has that
signature BMW element still there but
what was the most unexpected good way or
bad way I think the ionic 5 and uh even
the i7 I was not expecting it I didn't
expect it to be that great but um yeah I
I I'd say that these two cars of course
we had 27 cars and I don't remember the
names of all the cars I just remember
the jimney the iic because see and I
think the Volvo C40 recharge also I I
really loved that car because uh I think
it looks special on the outside and you
drive it it just a mad car in the sense
it's so quick so fast especially at that
price tag and I'm one of the fastest
cars and yeah I'm surprised you know
what what surprises me more is that I've
mentioned three cars and all three are
electric and I can't even remember apart
from probably the performante or the
jimney
any other ice car that felt as special
if you had to Define
what best of
2023 is as a whole not what makes a car
a best of 2023 because that's we've
covered but what is best of 2023 awards
for you how would you define that so I
think for me the 2023 Awards or best of
2023 I think we are rapidly moving
towards the electric cage and it's all
going to be about EVS probably I see in
the next 5 years we might not even have
an ice car there I think so I think so I
mean in the sense right now also I can't
think of anything else because whenever
I think that best of 2023 is all about
new cars the all new cars that I can
think of is they're all electric right I
told you like the cars that I can recall
they're all electric of course there are
a lot many cars the in NOA was there you
know the jimy was there of course there
were MKS the GLC all these fantastic
cars great cars but you sort of think
that they are outdated not because as
products but because of what passed them
so I think for me best of 2023 is a big
shift towards the future all right thank
you very
much but here's the thing I think you
know what what what what has happened
all this while is that you've grilled
all of us I think Dre was there isan was
there and then I'm here here and you've
been asking us questions and since
you're part of the jwy as well I think
it's only fair that we get some sort of
Revenge and we get to sit on that side
all right and I can probably throw some
difficult questions at you as well and
you can give us our take what do you
think all right I would be more than
obliged so let's swap seats let me see
how let's let's put you on the hot seat
let me show everyone how I look from the
other side yeah let's swap seats okay
okay so right here we are woo that's how
it feels like
exactly so I'm going to ask you a couple
of questions right sure maybe difficult
maybe easy because right now I think
you're now the expert because you sort
of Advantage here because you know
you've already asked us difficult
questions yes you have yeah big fun
exactly and uh plus you know what all of
us have spoken but it would be
interesting to know what you think about
all of these cars but the first question
that I have for you is what do you make
the best of 2023 because this is your
first time right with autox doing these
Awards we've done this a couple of times
and then again I'm adding another
question to it what for you
defines best of 2023 as in in a vehicle
in a car especially what do you see
something that that's something that
makes it the best of 2023 or the winner
in
general
right two very heavy loaded questions
right away so one thing at a time how
was the experience best of
2023 as you said my first
time I've tested every single car that's
on sale in the Indian market right now
and has been since the past decade but
I've not tested so many cars together at
the same time at the same day so for me
that that was really something U and and
it gives I realize it gives a unique
perspective because you sit say from a
tago eeve or a citrin EC3 and the next
car you're heading out in is BMWi i7 and
then you go in a FRS and then you have
an Urus performante waiting so it's a
wild mix of emotions my best friend as I
found out over the past couple of days
uh is the notes app in my phone makes my
life easier but yeah I mean it was it
was overwhelming it was exciting and uh
it was memorable i' I've seen autox
award tests for a long time I finally
get to be in one so it's a good feeling
and what do you think about the winner
like what makes the winner what's that
one thing that you look out for see as
I've already mentioned in the video I'm
also part of the bike jewelry right so
for me cars hold a different place right
it might
sound controversial but for me if a car
has to speak to me to my soul it really
has to be something because I have had
bikes really fast bikes which are
attainable for a lot more people because
of the price to Performance Factor so
for me it has to be like really
something but in order to be that really
something that bar stands just so much
higher right so that brings me to cars
like the Urus performante or the pora
Cayenne or the Lexus LX big Heavy
Hitters right but uh if I don't go that
high up in the price range or things
like that I see them as practical
options things that make your life
easier and if there's a car that can do
a bit of both I think that would qualify
as best of 2023 so I think you look for
a vehicle that's an allrounder of sorts
yes absolutely okay so speaking of which
tell me which of the 27 cars that we had
28 28 all right which one of those you
felt is like an
allrounder it does everything it's
perfect and in this I'm also including
the price because of course Urus
performante does everything including
off-roading but then it also comes at
that price right like a sensus so
sensible in the sense that does
everything perfectly what's that one car
that stood out for you which you thought
in the Indian market that's something
that very honestly the answer is bit
unconventional maybe but if I have to
really sensibly choose a car it would be
the eleate because like I mentioned the
car if it has to excelerate one thing
that usually for me is something that
costs a bomb but for as for a car that's
an allrounder i I think the Elevate is a
sum of its averages it it's it doesn't
stand out in any way I can't tell you
this is the best part about it but it
does so many things just better than
average that I think fall traes Jag of
fall traes so that stood out for me in
the sensible side of things but on the
allout side of
things it's it's a tie between three
electrics very surprisingly the i7 the
ionic and the C4 rege okay so what was
the most exciting car for you and what
was not so exciting or probably how do I
put it across the car that disappointed
you in the sense not lived up to the
expectations so I'll start with the bat
first it has to
be the thar rear whe drive for me I mean
everybody's going just said that for the
T the thar Community is going to be
after me
but there's a thar 4x4 and that's what
is a thar for me it's supposed to be 4x4
so it can do the extremely silly
off-road bit the rear wheel drive I
think they removed the drivetrain and
let the suspension be because it was
bouncing
everywhere it's very stiff the rear end
has only two doors lacks in practicality
but I'm willing to put up with all of
that if I have
to gain an off-road which I do with the
4x4 not with the rwd so once that's gone
it's only look at me in your rearview
mirror field which I think is limited
for me so I wasn't a big fan of that
experience plus it gets the smaller
engine it loses that punch that torquey
nature so that's the
bad the surprising bit the most fun I
had was the mg Comet
e okay that's yes I mean of course you
have fun in the porak cayen and stupidly
F C40 and the ice the mg comment we've
got our camera crew here I I know they
were tracking the tracking shots of the
car maybe we have them on the screen now
the slalom course that small wheelbase
skinny tires and me inside it it just
looks funny because I'm a decently sized
guy right so when I sit in the comet
it's like I'm going to drive this thing
and it would over steer and under steer
and it won't break so it was it was
really silly for me it still did 100K
which is impressive but it was it was a
lot of fun not from performance
standpoint but it was like I just have
to turn the wheel and it would spin
around right and at that area I could do
that so it stood out that's that's a
very interesting take because I heard no
one saying good things about no it's a
good car but I'd say not fun I'd say no
no it's not no it's it's very practical
yeah I'm not saying it's a fun car to
drive it's an enthusias car I'm just
saying it's so bloody practical and
built to a cost that when you have it at
a facility like IAD what the concoction
makes is a stupid experience right like
that I would if I were testing the comet
EV for a review and I have it in office
I'm commuting I'm testing range and
things like that sure but when I have
when I'm going all out on a track with
Banking and slal and emergency changes
it was okay so that I'm going
to ask you the last question right which
again when you look at the that whole
lineup all those cars they
parked so what's what do you make out of
it what do you think of the Indian
market in general when you know that as
a tester this is what you have to test
and this is what the market wants this
is what we have available and this is
what there for the buyer or customer
anyone in general so what was your
impression of that and in
2023 where do you think the Indian Auto
industry
stands that's a very good question I
have to
okay not trying to make it very long see
testing cars I'm sure for you as well is
a dream that's why we are here that's
why we've made it our
livelihood it's a childhood
dream but testing 28 cars in a couple of
days that's a nightmare for a Critic we
also critics at the end of the day right
so for me when I look at the lineup it
was a mix of a dream and a nightmare for
me because I want to enjoy but then I
have to critique right I have to
critique the performante as well as I
have have to critique the FRS and the
jimney across the Spectrum but for the
market Indian market I think it's wild
like wild is the word if you talk about
SUVs we have Lexus LX like look at that
but you also have performante what's
going on with that and you have the
Cayenne but the i7 which is electric is
going stupid fast
so there is a demand for all of these
that's why they exist and are here on
sale and when you look at just the
demands starting from bottom to top
they're mad like it's the same situation
like if I if I'm a person who's planning
to buy a car I'm not an autoc critique
you are I ask you bro I have 16 17 lakh
rupees what should I buy you'll be like
what do you want you want a nexton V Max
an electric SUV you want a fancy jazzed
up hatch bag you want a budget sedan
it's wi so I think the Indian market is
silly
but it's good for everyone everybody
wins because there's always something
yeah it's time to wrap this up this up
so thank you very
much thank you very much yes for asking
me the questions next video out will
have our winners right yes so stay tuned
to the auto X YouTube channel we'll be
putting out a video which will tell you
the winners of both cars and two
wheelers and which were the 10 that made
the
cut amongst 41
contenders that's a big task and all
those 41s cars and bikes and scooter
they're all of the topnotch quality so
it's been it's it's going to be tough
for us yeah but you'll soon see which
ones came out on top this video should
have helped you get an idea of which
one's going to come out on top but the
good thing about our Awards is as you
would have heard Dru say right at the
beginning the scores are averaged out so
there's no bias so it truly is the best
and you will be able to catch all our
scores by catching hold of our latest
issue of the autox magazine that's just
how we are we publish the scores so
thank you very much for watching this
video making this far make sure you like
it share it with your friends in case
they want to know about one of the cars
we spoke about and make sure you let us
know which one would be your pick for
the best of
2023 goodbye
[Music]
bye